Finding Aid for the Ojai Music Festival Records PASC-M.0277
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Business Papers, 1940s-1990s; Series 3.
  - Finance, Subseries 8.
    - Payroll '94, 1994; papers (Box 80, Folder 4)
      Payroll information, including federal/state tax forms, ledgers, memos
    - Petty cash, 1994; papers, receipts (Box 97, Folder 3)
      Receipts and petty cash requests from the business office of the Ojai Festival.
    - Phone lines and hook-up, 1992; Contracts and bills (Box 39, Folder 21)
      Contracts and bills from Pacific Bell.
    - Production budgets '92, '93, '94, 1992-1994; faxes, spreadsheets, papers (Box 27, Folder 5)
      Planning and analysis for production costs for the Festivals between 1992 and 1994
    - Reimbursements, 1994; papers, receipts (Box 97, Folder 2)
      Spreadsheets, receipts, requests for reimbursements. Documentation related to business expenses for the Festival.
    - Statement of Security Account, June 1, 1985-June 28, 1985; Papers (Box 7, Folder 9)
      Security bank statement and tax forms for Ojai Festival.
    - Treasurer's Report 1966-1967 F.C. Embshoff, Tr., July 6, 1967; Bound papers (Box 5, Folder 8)
      Accounting records for the 1966-67 season of the Ojai Festival
    - Vendor receipts and proposals, 1994; papers (Box 97, Folder 4)
      Receipts, proposals and correspondence to/from vendors: Paper Moon Press, US Postal Service, Quill, Pacific Bell Telephone, Sprint.
    - Women's Committee bank statement, 7/3/93-8/31/93; bank statement and cancelled checks (Box 2, Folder 1)
      banking records relevant to the Women's Committe of Ojai and the thrift shop
    - Women's Committee bank statement, 7/1/93-7/30/93; bank statement and cancelled checks (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Women's Committee bank statement, 5/29/93-6/30/93; bank statement and cancelled checks (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Women's Committee bank statement, 5/1/93-5/28/93; bank statement and cancelled checks (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Women's Committee bank statement, 4/1/93-4/30/93; bank statement and cancelled checks (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Women's Committee bank statement, 2/27/93-3/31/93; bank statement and cancelled checks (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Women's Committee bank statement, 1/30/93-2/26/93; bank statement and cancelled checks (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Women's Committee bank statement, 12/1/92-12/31/92; bank statement and cancelled checks (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Women's Committee bank statement, 10/31/92-11/30/92; bank statement and cancelled checks (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Women's Committee bank statement, 10/1/92-10/30/92; bank statement and cancelled checks (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Women's Committee bank statement, 9/1/92-9/30/92; bank statement and cancelled checks (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Women's Committee bank statement, 8/18/92-8/31/92; bank statement and cancelled checks (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Women's Committee bank statement, 7/16/92-8/17/92; bank statement and cancelled checks (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Women's Committee bank statement, 7/1/94-7/29/94; bank statement and cancelled checks (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Women's Committee bank statement, 6/1/94-6/30/94; bank statement and cancelled checks (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Women's Committee bank statement, 4/30/94-5/31/94; bank statement and cancelled checks (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Women's Committee bank statement, 4/1/94-4/29/94; bank statement and cancelled checks (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Women's Committee bank statement, 3/1/94-3/31/94; bank statement and cancelled checks (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Women's Committee bank statement, 2/1/94-2/28/94; bank statement and cancelled checks (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Women's Committee bank statement, 1/1/94-1/31/94; bank statement and cancelled checks (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Women's Committee bank statement, 12/1/93-12/31/93; bank statement and cancelled checks (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Women's Committee bank statement, 10/30/93-11/30/93; bank statement and cancelled checks (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Women's Committee bank statement, 10/1/93-10/29/93; bank statement and cancelled checks (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Women's Committee bank statement, 9/1/93-9/30/93; bank statement and cancelled checks (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Women's Committee bank statements, 6/1/95-6/30/95; Bank statements, cancelled checks, receipts (Box 2, Folder 27)
      Banking records
    - Women's Committee bank statements, 4/29/95-5/31/95; Bank statements, cancelled checks, receipts (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Women's Committee bank statements, 4/1/95-4/28/95; Bank statements, cancelled checks, receipts (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Women's Committee bank statements, 3/1/95-3/31/95; Bank statements, cancelled checks, receipts (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Women's Committee bank statements, 2/1/95-2/28/95; Bank statements, cancelled checks, receipts (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Women's Committee bank statements, 12/31/94-1/31/95; Bank statements, cancelled checks, receipts (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Women's Committee bank statements, 12/1/94-12/30/94; Bank statements, cancelled checks, receipts (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Women's Committee bank statements, 11/1/94-11/30/94; Bank statements, cancelled checks, receipts (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Women's Committee bank statements, 10/1/94-10/31/94; Bank statements, cancelled checks, receipts (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Women's Committee bank statements, 9/1/94-9/30/94; Bank statements, cancelled checks, receipts (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Women's Committee bank statements, 7/30/94-8/31/94; Bank statements, cancelled checks, receipts (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Finance-- Bank Statements, Subseries 9.
    - Bank Statements, 1996; bank statements in original envelopes (Box 3, Folder 5)
      13 envelopes of bank statements.
  - Chronological Files, Subseries 11.
    Arrangement note
    Arranged chronologically.
    Each month's records has an inventory of the contents (memos and their recipients, receipts, etc.)
    - Chron File, 1990-1991; papers (Box 127)
      Correspondence, press releases, and general business records that were kept in the Festival's Chron file.
    - Chron File, 1991-1992; papers (Box 128)
    - Chron File, 1993; papers (Box 129)
    - Chron File, 1992-1993; papers (Box 130)
    - Chron File,FY 95,Vol II, 1995 February; papers (Box 75, Folder 2)
      Memos, minutes, and all files relevant to general business.
      Each month's records has an inventory of the contents, eg memos and their recipients, receipts, etc.
    - Chron File,FY 95,Vol II,Dec 94, Jan 95, 1994-1995; papers (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Chron File,FY 97-98, 1997-1998; papers (Box 109)
    - Chron Vol IV August 1995, 1995 August; papers, invitations, correspondence (Box 77, Folder 3)
      Correspondence, sample invitations, press releases and other general business records from the general chron file kept by the Festival.
      Each month has a detailed inventory of the records.
    - Chron Vol IV July 1995, 1995 July; papers (Box 77, Folder 2)
      Correspondence and other general business records from the general chron file kept by the Festival.
    - Chron Vol IV June 1995, 1995 June; papers, invitations, correspondence (Box 77, Folder 1)
      Correspondence, sample invitations, and other general business records from the general chron file kept by the Festival.
    - Chron Vol IV November/December 1995, 1995 November-December; papers, invitations, correspondence (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Chron Vol IV September/October 1995, papers, invitations, correspondence (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Chron Vol V April 1996, papers (Box 76, Folder 4)
      Each month includes a master inventory of the records contained.
    - Chron Vol V February 1996, papers (Box 76, Folder 2)
      Correspondence, calendars of events, and general business records that were kept in the Festival's Chron file.
    - Chron Vol V January 1996, papers (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Chron Vol V July 1996, papers (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Chron Vol V June 1996, papers (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Chron Vol V March 1996, papers (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Chron Vol V May 1996, papers (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Publicity, Subseries 12.
    - Ad Invoicing, 1994-1995; Papers (Box 23, Folder 6)
      Invoices and records for organizations advertising in the 1995 Festival.
    - Advertising, 1993; papers, brochures, correspondence, festival program (Box 29, Folder 1)
      Materials related to Ojai Festival program advertisers.
    - Advertising, 1995; Contracts, correspondence (Box 34, Folder 6)
      Ads placed by the Ojai Festival in other programs/publications
    - Advertising, 1993; papers, programs, brochures (Box 61, Folder 4)
      Lists of members of the press, ad samples, brochures, Ojai programs
    - Advertising, 1992; papers and brochures (Box 87, Folder 6)
      Drafts and final versions of advertisements to appear in 1992 Festival program.
    - Advertising Contracts, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 4)
      Contracts and rate information related to advertisers in the Ojai program.
    - Advertising Festival '95, 1994-1996; Papers (Box 23, Folder 7)
      Advertising guides for organizations; rate sheets for advertising space
      Covers Festival '95 with a few items relevant to the '96 Festival
    - Press and Advertising Festival '95, 1995; Papers and brochures (Box 23, Folder 4)
      Press kits and information for '95 Festival
    - Press contacts/Status reports, 1988-1991; Drafts and records (Box 40, Folder 23)
      Related to relationships with members of the press and publicity tracking
    - Press events; publicity workshops, 1992; papers (Box 87, Folder 2)
      Correspondence and papers related to upcoming press events and a public relations workshop (all held in 1992).
    - Press packs 1992, papers (Box 87, Folder 5)
      Information for members of the press, including statistics about the festival, performance information and general information about the Ojai Valley.
    - Press Quotes-Festival '94 Press Attendance-Festival '95, 1994-95; Papers (Box 23, Folder 2)
      Press quotes (newspaper, etc) from '94 Festival; press attendance/reservation forms for '95 Festival
    - Press receptions and reservations, 1992; papers, brochures (Box 87, Folder 4)
      Related to receptions held for members of the press surrounding the 1992 Ojai Festival.
    - Press releases FY 91, 1990-1991; papers, labels (Box 81, Folder 4)
      Press releases and mailing labels for the 1991 season of the Ojai Music Festival.
    - Press reservations and ticketing, 1992; papers and cards (Box 87, Folder 3)
      Reservation cards and lists related to individual members of the press attending various Ojai concerts and events.
    - Press tickets/housing 1988, Contracts, correspondence, drafts (Box 40, Folder 22)
      Forms for press tickets and housing
    - Publication ideas; potential marketing pieces, 1990's; brochures, news clippings (Box 34, Folder 5)
      information about publications such as Los Angeles magazine; sample marketing pieces
    - Publicity, 1986-1988; news clippings, photographs, papers (Box 83, Folder 2)
      Press releases and clippings related to 1986-88 Festivals, as well as information about other arts programs.
    - Unprocessed Press Books, 2004-2006 (Box 113)
  - Programs, Subseries 13.
    - Program 2, 1992; Papers (Box 43, Folder 3)
      Drafts and corrections for the concert program of Program II, held on May 30, 1992.
    - Program Book, 1991; papers, programs (Box 72, Folder 4)
      Drafts of program pages for the 1991 season; two final Festival programs
    - Program Book Materials, 1993; correspondence, faxes, papers (Box 28, Folder 3)
      Materials related to 1993 program, including artist biographies and donor lists
    - Program drafts, 1993; correspondence, faxes, papers (Box 28, Folder 4)
      Materials related to 1993 program, including artist biographies and donor lists; drafts of final program with corrections
    - Program I, 1992; papers (Box 43, Folder 2)
      Drafts and corrections of concert program for Program I of the 1992 Festival.
    - Program three draft, June 2000; drafts of program (Box 37, Folder 1)
      Covers program 3, held on June 2, 2000.
      Music by Ravel.
    - Programs 3-5, 1992; Papers (Box 43, Folder 4)
      Corrected and edited concert programs for Programs III-V, held in May of 1992.
    - Unprocessed Programs, 2004-2006 (Box 113)
      Three programs.
  - Production Files, Subseries 14.
    - Assorted Unprocessed Papers, 1996-1997 (Box 109)
    - Assorted Unprocessed Papers, 1996-1997 (Box 110)
    - Assorted Unprocessed Papers, 2000-2001 (Box 111)
    - Assorted Unprocessed Papers, 1999-2000 (Box 112)
    - Assorted Unprocessed Papers (Box 113)
    - Assorted Unprocessed Papers, 1992 (Box 114)
    - Assorted Unprocessed Papers, 1996 (Box 122)
    - Unprocessed Papers, 1997 (Box 118, copy 1)
    - Unprocessed Papers, 1997 (Box 119)
    - Unprocessed Papers, 1996-1997 (Box 120)
    - Unprocessed Papers, 1996 (Box 121)
- Programs, Series 4.
  - 1982 Program, Annotated program (Box 67, Folder 1)
    Program that indicates which cassettes correspond to each piece.
    Covers Friday, June 4 through Sunday, June 6.
  - 1992 Programs: notes, edits, papers (Box 43, Folder 1)
    Full concert programs for the 1992 season with corrections and edits.
  - Festival 1992 program inserts, programs, papers (Box 44, Folder 1)
    Programs and drafts, including invoices for ads in the program.
  - Ojai Festival 1985 Program, May 31, 1985-June 2, 1985; pamphlet (Box 96, Folder 7)
    Festival program for the 39th season, 1985. Includes program notes and annotations for many of the programs recorded on the reels in Box 96.
  - Program Inserts 2000, programs, photocopies (Box 36, Folder 1)
    Related to inserts for festival programs. Translations of libretti, etc.
- Correspondence, Series 5.
  - '93 Arts Administration Internship, 1993; papers (Box 59, Folder 6)
    Correspondence regarding internship at Ojai (sent to Cal State Northridge, UCLA, etc).
  - Composer Correspondence (General), 1984-1991; papers, brochures (Box 69, Folder 5)
    Correspondence and artist biographies for Ojai seasons 1984-1991.
  - Letters from children, 1993 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    Photocopied letters from elementary school children regarding Ojai performances.
  - Letters from children, 1992-1995; papers (Box 81, Folder 3)
    Handwritten cards and letters from schoolchildren regarding performances by members of the Ventura County Symphony.
- Artists, Series 6.
  - Adams, John, 1989-1991; photographs, biographies, news clippings (Box 42, Folder 8)
    Information about the composer/director who joined the Festival in 1990.
  - Alvarez, Javier, 1993; photographs, biographies (Box 42, Folder 9)
    Information about the Mexican composer and clarinetist.
  - Ara Guzeliman, 1992; photographs, biographies, news clippings (Box 49, Folder 10)
    Information about conductor Guzeliman, and his engagements with the LA Philharmonic and Ojai Festival.
  - Arditti String Quartet I, 1988-1989; press releases, news clippings, correspondence (Box 42, Folder 5)
    Related to the string quartet performing at the 1989 Ojai Festival.
  - Arditti String Quartet II, 1988-1989; photographs, biographies (Box 42, Folder 6)
    Further information about the Arditti String Quartet, including their repertoire.
  - Armstrong, Nancy, 1980's; photographs, biographies (Box 42, Folder 7)
    Information about the soprano.
  - Artist Bios, 1991; papers, photographs (Box 74, Folder 5)
    Biographies, photographs and resumes of various artists during the 1991 Festival, including Susan Carlin Montgomery, David Gordon, and Charles Neidich.
  - Artist bios I, 1990's; photographs, biographical sketches (Box 41, Folder 3)
    National press and biographical sketches of musicians performing at Ojai during the 1990's
  - Artist bios II, 1990's; photographs, biographical sketches, news clippings (Box 41, Folder 4)
    Photographs and national press regarding artists performing at Ojai during the 1990s
  - Artists general I, 1991-1992; photographs, biographical sketches (Box 41, Folder 7)
    Press kits from managers/agents regarding musicians; programs from non-Ojai performances
  - Artists general II, 1991-1992; photographs, biographical sketches (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - ASCAP 1991, papers, brochures (Box 70, Folder 3)
    Contracts and information about ASCAP regarding use of music and licensing issues.
  - Barry Brisk, 1981; photographs, biographies, correspondence (Box 42, Folder 4)
    Related to Barry Brisk, assistant conductor of the 1981 Festival.
  - Knowles, Amy, 1993; photocopies and originals (Box 31, Folder 6)
    Articles and information about Amy Knowles, flutist.
  - Schub, Andre-Michel, 1981-1982; photographs, biographical sketches (Box 39, Folder 14)
    Information about the French-American pianist.
- Clippings--Individuals--Performers, Series 7.
  - Artists/Press 1980s-90s, 1980's-1990's; Photocopied news clippings, correspondence (Box 41, Folder 2)
    Clippings and biographical sketches of artists performing at Ojai in the 1980s and 1990s
  - Christopher O'Reilly, 1989; photographs, biographies, correspondence (Box 38, Folder 13)
    Related to pianist Christopher O'Reilly
  - D artists, 1980s-1990s; Press kits and biographical sketches (Box 49, Folder 4)
    Information about the Debussy Trio, Paul Dresher Ensemble, and Anthony Davis.
  - Hester (Robison accomp.); Husa, 1994; biographical information (Box 49, Folder 12)
    Correspondence with Paula Robison's accompanist, Thomas Hester; brochure about Czech composer Karel Husa.
  - James Tuggle, 1980; Photographs, biographical sketch (Box 40, Folder 12)
    Sketch of conductor James Tuggle, who was involved with the 1980 Festival.
  - Peter Nagy 1981, photographs, biographies, correspondence (Box 38, Folder 12)
    Related to Hungarian pianist Peter Nagy.
- Clippings--Individuals--Philanthropists, Series 9.
  - Huntington Hartford Foundation, Subseries 1.
    - Hartford clippings and writings, 1960s; news clippings and papers (Box 64, Folder 3)
      Articles about Hartford, Rustic Canyon, and publication by Hartford: Has God Been Insulted Here?
    - Hartford foundation papers, 1950's; index cards, papers (Box 64, Folder 5)
      Information about gifts to the foundation; correspondence
    - Hartford Foundation reports, 1960s; correspondence, brochures (Box 65, Folder 3)
      Information about closing of the Foundation and some of the fellows it hosted.
    - HHF Fellows, 1960s-1970s; news clippings and papers (Box 65, Folder 1)
      News clippings and correspondence regarding fellows at the Huntington Hartford Foundation
    - Huntington Hartford materials, 1950s; postcards and index cards (Box 64, Folder 6)
      Postcards of the Hartford estate; index cards of gifts to the foundation
    - Huntington Hartford press clippings, 1965-1992; news clippings (Box 64, Folder 1)
      Information about Huntington Hartford: his accumulation of wealth, establishment and closing of foundation, etc.
- Clippings--Groups--Performance ensembles, Series 10.
  - Aman Folk Ensemble, 1983-1984; Brochures, correspondence (Box 42, Folder 10)
    Information about the Aman Folk Ensemble, who performed in the 1984 Festival.
- Ojai Clippings, 1940s-1980s; Series 11.
  - "The Ojai" old newspaper, May 14, 1953; Newspaper (Box 4, Folder 3)
    One copy of the Thursday, May 14 edition of "The Ojai"
    Cover story entitled, "Seventh Ojai Festival Season of Drama, Music May 21-24."
  - '92 Jazz at Ojai I, 1992; papers (Box 53, Folder 8)
    press releases, correspondence, ticket information
    See '92 Jazz at Ojai II for remainder of materials.
  - '92 Jazz at Ojai II, 1992; papers (Box 53, Folder 3)
    Mailing lists, programs and information about the Jazz Festival.
  - '92 Jazz at Ojai Press/Publicity/Photographs, 1992; papers (Box 53, Folder 2)
    Press releases, correspondence, news clippings regarding the 1992 Jazz at Ojai series.
  - Art foundations and colonies, 1966-1992; news clippings and correspondence (Box 64, Folder 2)
    Information about United States-based art foundations and colonies
  - Articles and programs, 1960's?; Laminated programs and articles (Box 24, Folder 5)
    Programs and articles related to Festival. No years.
    One article mentions Juilliard String Quartet.
  - Artists Housing Contracts Transportation 1992, correspondence, contracts, drafts, faxes (Box 38, Folder 5)
    related to artists, housing and transportation. communication with agents.
  - Arts press general, 1968-1980; newspaper clippings and music programs (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Arts press that does not relate directly to the Ojai Festival, such as government funding information for the arts.
  - Beatrice Wood Play: "Torch in the Sky", 1993; papers (Box 53, Folder 5)
    Planning materials for play to be presented in conjunction with the Ojai Festival.
  - Festival planning and programs, 1947, 1958, 1952; Clippings, photographs, scrapbook pages (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Loose scrapbook pages and clippings related to 1948 and 1952 Festival.
    Includes original planning booklets preceding the 1947 Festival.
  - FY 1983 Press Notices, 1982-1983; photocopies and original press clippings (Box 40, Folder 24)
    Press regarding 1982 Festival.
  - Interim Series Ticket Order Form Festival '93, June 1993; papers (Box 59, Folder 2)
    Drafts of ticket order forms
  - Jazz '93 Press prep, 1992; newspaper (Box 53, Folder 1)
    October 2, 1992 issue of GP (Going Places) segment of Ventura County Star-Free press.
  - Jazz '93 Other contacts/vendors/etc, 1993; papers, brochures (Box 62, Folder 7)
    Information from printers/poster makers.
  - Loose scrapbook pages, 1965-1995; news clippings, papers (Box 73, Folder 6)
    Photocopied and original press clippings from seasons ranging from the 1960s to the 1990s.
    Includes articles about Michael Tilson Thomas.
  - Magazines, 1958-1977 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    Writer's Digest, Saturday Review, Opera News, Music Magazine, Smithsonian
    These are complete magazines, not clippings.
  - Magazines 1992, magazines (Box 85, Folder 1)
    Full issues of magazines featuring articles about the Festival.
    Magazine titles: Club & Sports Society (April 1992); On the Air Magazine (June 1992)
  - Messiaen-Loriod, 1985-1986; itineraries, press clippings, invoices, photocopies of photos (Box 38, Folder 7)
    Related to Messiaen's involvement at Ojai and subsequent death; information about pianist Yvonne Loriod.
  - Miscellaneous press, 1950-1986; clippings and papers (Box 22, Folder 1)
    newspaper clippings, programs, and calendars
    news clippings used to be in scrapbooks
  - News clippings, 1950's; original and photocopied articles (Box 24, Folder 3)
    Articles glued onto papers and cardstock relevant to Ojai Festivals of the 1950's.
  - News clippings, 1950's; Loose scrapbook pages (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - News clippings, 1970's; Photocopied articles (Box 24, Folder 6)
    Clippings, some loose and some taped/glued to paper.
    One article about Aaron Copland at 75 and his involvement with Ojai.
  - News clippings, 1980's; Photocopied articles (Box 24, Folder 7)
    Two articles, in German and one in English.
    German/Austrian article entitled, "Das kalifornische Salzburg."
  - News clippings, 1992-1993; papers, news clippings (Box 85, Folder 3)
    Photocopies of news clippings and original articles.
    Most related to Pierre Boulez, Peter Sellars, and general programming.
  - News clippings, pamphlets, advertisements, 1950s-1960s; original and photocopied articles, pamphlets, ads (Box 24, Folder 8)
    Miscellaneous articles, not all relevant to Festival.
    Includes print ads from magazines, not relevant to Festival (eg Northern Pacific Railway from National Geographic)
  - OFCOE 1992/93 Press Clippings, 1992-1993; papers (Box 62, Folder 2)